jqwidgets.com 2019-10-17

# Privacy Policy - Javascript, HTML5, jQuery Widgets

#### General information

The current privacy policy is provided by jQWidgets Ltd. jQWidgets Ltd is the administrator of your personal data within the meaning of the applicable data protection legislation. This Privacy Policy aims to identify the types of personal and anonymous data we process in the course of our activity in relation to this website and other websites under our brand. It also explains for what purposes and on what basis we do such processing. In case you have any questions regarding the protection of your personal data, you may use the contact information listed at the end of this Privacy Policy. 

#### Collection of information through server logs

You can visit and use our websites without sharing any personal information. When you visit this website we only collect anonymous data through the web server logs and analytics software. The collected information is used to ensure trouble-free operation of the website site, to improve the product offerings, analyze and optimize the content of this web site, provide additional service and products improvements. The type of information collected includes, but is not limited to, display type, operating system, browser type and version, time of visit. Аll data exchanged with our servers is transmitted via an encrypted connection using HTTPS protocol, TLS 1.2

#### Information collected for billing, technical support, and forum participation

Some of the services provided on this website require user registration and collection of personal information. For example, the participation and contributions to the online forums requires registration. We also collect personal information when you download and purchase software licenses, contact our staff, request support by filling support request forms, and when you register to participate in the forums and blogs. We use this information for orders fulfillment, billing purposes, subscription renewal notifications and to answer technical support requests. This information may be accessed by some members of our staff as well as people providing technical and professional services to us by contract (e.g. accountants, lawyers). We reserve the right to use this information for product announcements, newsletter updates, promotions, technical support and additional service offers. However, we do not share, rent, or sell any personal with third parties for promotional purposes. You may choose to opt-out of receiving our own product announcements and newsletters by sending an email to our technical support staff or following the opt-out links in our newsletter and announcement emails. We make every possible effort to protect your personal information by using encryption and other methods. Nevertheless, you should keep in mind that the transmission of information over the Internet has risks and may never be completely secure. 

#### Use of analytics software

We uses Google Analytics, a service provided by Google Inc, that allows us to analyze the usage of this website and optimize its content. The information generated about your use of the website may be transmitted to Google servers (including servers located outside of the European Union). Google provides a free browser plug-in which allows website visitors the ability to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytic. You may download the plug-in here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

#### Use of third party payment processors

We use third-party payment service providers (“Payment Processors”) to manage online payments. In particular we use Skrill and PayPal. You may also choose to place an order and submit a payment via bank transfer. Depending on the selected method of payment, the payment service provider or bank institution may collect data themselves. In this case, the privacy policy of the respective bank or payment service provider applies. 

#### Data transfer and processing

We may store and process some of the collected information on servers and cloud infrastructure located within the EU and the United States. All information is transferred in encrypted form. When you opt-in, register, contact us, and place orders and provide personal information, you consent that the provided information may be transferred, processed and stored within the European Union or United States. 

#### Information retention

Your information will be retained for as long as your account is active with us and we continue to provide you with services. In certain cases we may need to retain and use information to comply with legal obligations, to enforce our terms of use and license agreements and resolve customer disputes. 

#### Use of web cookies. Cookies control.

To improve and optimize the experience on our sites, we use “cookies”. These are small text files containing data that can be placed on your device. Among other things, cookies allow a website to know when a device has visited before. Cookies may also store certain user settings and preferences. For example, whether the preferred background of the website you visited is dark or light. You may configure your cookie preferences from your browser. You may also choose to completely disable cookies. All modern browsers provide this functionality. You can learn more about cookies here: <https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie>

#### Account information, opt-out, account close and data erase requests

In compliance with EU GDPR, you have the following rights:

– Information request: You have the right to request information about the personal data stored and processed about you.  
– Correction of data: If you believe the information we have stored about you is incorrect, please let us know and we will change it accordingly.  
– Restrict Processing: Under certain circumstances, you may request us to restrict the processing of your personal data. In theses cases we will discontinue the active use of your data. However, the data may not be deleted definitively.  
– Erasure of data: You may send us a request to delete your own personal data stored by us.  
– Data transfer: You may send us a request to receive a copy of your data stored with us. We will send you a copy of the data stored with us in a text file format by email.  
– Right of objection: You may object to the processing of your personal data.

You may also send us a request to cancel your registration, close your user account. You may also choose to opt-out of receiving promotional and marketing materials by requesting an opt-out by email or following the unsubscribe links in emails sent to you. For opt-out, account close or records erase requests, please send an email to [support@jqwidgets.com](mailto:support@jqwidgets.com)

If you choose to exercise your right to be forgotten or place a data correction request, please make sure to provide emails and other user handles you’ve used to register, download, communicate with our staff or participate in the online forums. 

#### Contact us

If you have additional questions about the processing, collection, use of anonymous or personal data, or requests for information, correction, opt-out or erasure of data, please contact us by e-mail at [support@jqwidgets.com](mailto:support@jqwidgets.com)

In addition you may write us by regular mail:

jQWidgets LTD  
10 Acad. Metodi Popov str., bl. 63  
Sofia, Bulgaria

If you believe that we are violating your rights in relation to the protection of your personal data, please contact us immediately using one of the methods specified above. You also have the right to complain to the competent supervisory authority in the Republic of Bulgaria – the Personal Data Protection Commission.
